JERRIN BRIGHT

LINKEDIN | PORTFOLIO | GITHUB | MAIL | SCHOLAR | NGO | BLOGS

PERSONAL PROFILE STATEMENT

I am a versatile and self-motivated engineer highly skilled in **Autonomous Systems** and **Robotic Real-time Perception** for aerial and ground robots. I aim to work on research-oriented organizations that utilize and contribute in honing my skills.

QUALIFICATIONS

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, India Bachelors of Technology in Mechanical Engineering June 2018-April 2022 (expected) Cumulative GPA: 8.25/10.0

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Design and Simulation Tools Programming Tools Other Tools Gazebo, RViz, MATLAB, SOFA, Fusion360, SolidWorks, Proteus Python, C++, Embedded System, Shell, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP ROS, Git, Movelt, OpenCV, TensorFlow, PyTorch, PCL, Heroku

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Globalink Research Intern @ McMaster University, Ontario, Canada

Starting July 2021

Designing and testing software for controlling a pneumatically-powered soft robot arm. It will acquire real-time data from several sensors, and implement a suitable controller (e.g., model predictive control). (Supervised by Prof. Gary Bone)

Summer Research Intern @ Arizona State University, Phoenix, USA 🗷

Starting May 2021

Using laser scanning, photogrammetry to digitalize environments via visualizing data collected from sensors fusing into a unified system. It will be processed to provide insights to builders, stewards. (**Supervised by Prof. Thomas Czerniawski**)

Autonomous System Developer (ASD) - Intern @ Aero2Astro, India 🗷

Oct 2020-Present

Developing ROS based autonomous navigation firmware using Visual Inertial SLAM concepts for indoor environment. Implementation was based on Sensor Fusion (EKF) and is aimed to eradicate GPS thus making the firmware more reliable.

Project Research Intern @ Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan City, Taiwan ☑

April – June 2020

Built a robust smart parking system using semantic segmentation with Conv. Conditional Random Fields and Atrous Convolution enhancing the visual capability of the system.

(Supervised by Prof. Wei-Tyng Hong)

Team Captain and Co-Founder @ Atom Robotics, VIT Chennai, India 🗷

Jan 2019-Present

An Intelligent Robotics & Satellite exploration team consisting of 50+ aspiring young minds. The team focuses on Intelligent ground vehicles targeting IGVC, USA; Planetary Aerial System targeting IPAS, MSSA; Satellites targeting Can-Sat, USA.

RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

Jerrin Bright et al 2021 IOP Conf. Ser.: Mater. Sci. Eng. 1012 012019 2

Optimization of quadcopter frame using generative design and comparison with DJI F450 drone frame **Jerrin Bright et al (Currently in Progress)**

A Novel Dynamic Obstacle Avoidance Approach using Panoptic Segmentation and Optical Flow techniques

RESEARCH PROJECT

| 3D Pose Estimation using Stereo Visual Odometry ☑ |
|---|
| Techniques: SLAM, FLANN, ORB, PnP, RANSAC, KLT Optical Flow |

Feb – April 2021

Autonomous MAV enhanced with door-to-door delivery topographies ☑

Dec – Jan 2020

Techniques: ROS, PID Control, Gazebo, RViz, Navigation, AMCL, Path Planning

Sep – Oct 2020

SLAM embedded AGV for autonomous navigation

Techniques: SLAM, ROS, Kinect + IMU, Sensor Fusion, Gazebo, RViz, Mapping, Path Planning

00p 000 2020

Intelligent Visual Robotic Inspection system for fault detection

Jan – Feb 2021

Techniques: LBPH, Deep Learning, Fused Networks, Attention embedded Residual Network

May - Oct 2020

Techniques: Designing and Simulation, IOT, Encoders, Raspberry Pi, Communication

ACCOLADES AND RECOGNITION

Vestium- Smart Robotic Closet

Outstanding Research Paper Award ☑ Recognized Galactic Problem Solver ☑ Second Runner-up, IEEE Hackathon ☑

RIACT 2020 International Conference NASA International Space Challenge Apogee'21, BITS Pilani Campus

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Machine Learning Contributor Contributing ML blogs to various blog-based companies. Have published 13 blogs.

Madras Scientific Research Foundation, NGO Spreading awareness on robotics in schools, amongst unprivileged kids **National Service Scheme** Active Member of Indian Government sponsored public service program.

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineer Active Member of Robotics and Automation Society (RAS).